Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series IV: General correspondence, 1931-1969, 253028
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 253029
    - Academic correspondence, 1936-1949, 253066 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Clegg family, 1941-1954, 253065 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Clopper, Edward Nicholas, 1942-1954, 253064 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Connerly, Doris, 1952-1953, 253063 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Coulter, Ellis Merton, 1942-1948, 253062 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Craig, Alta M., 1953, 253061 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Cross, Wilford Oakland, 1951-1955, 253060 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Culpepper, Eva Jean Hyndman, 1931, 253059 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Davidson, Dixie, 1953, 253058 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Deats, Mrs. E.T., 1942, 253057 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - DeForest, Lionel Theodore, 1936-1939, 253056 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Denison, Charles C., n.d., 253055 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Dix, William S., 1951, 253054 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Dobie, J. Frank, 1941-1958, 253053 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Douglas, Joseph B., 1941, 253052 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Druitt, Florence, 1943, 253051 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Dunlop, William Ernest, 1933, 253050 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Dutton, Meirick, 1951-1952, 253049 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Edwards, Benjamin Franklin Jr., 1943, 253048 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Federal, 1941-1949, 253047 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Fletcher, Herbert, 1943-1955, 253046 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Flye, James Harold, 1938-1953, 253045 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Forbis, Dorothy, 1943-1946, 253044 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Ford, Hamilton, 1951-1952, 253043 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Forristall, Margaret S., 1944, 253042 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Foster, William Thomas, 1940-1943, 253041 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Francesca, SSJD, 1938, 253040 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Frank, Anton J., 1947-1952, 253039 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Freund, Max, 1953-1954, 253038 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Fullerton, Henry Lee, 1940-1952, 253037 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Goode, William Josiah, 1940-1952, 253036 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - (regarding) Harris, DeWitt Clinton, 253035 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - McGee, William Sears, 1953, 253034 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Religious, 1936-1950, 253033 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - State of Texas, 1940-1948, 253032 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, Sidney, Brother Dominic OHC, 1937, 253031 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Muir, Andrew Forest: Estate correspondence, 1969-1971, 253030 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Series V: Alphabetical subject research files, 1935-1969, 252462
  Dates appearing after a person's name often reflect their birth and death dates, not the contents of the file. The files themselves were created and maintained by Andrew Forest Muir circa 1935-1969, with subjects covering a wide range dates, circa 1750-1969, bulk 1800s.
  - Abud, Henry (priest), 253027 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Affleck, Thomas, 253026 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Notes on enslaved people and real estate records, 1840s-1850s
  - Albert, Charles H., 253025 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    San Augustine County, Texas, deacon, 1850s. Anglican priest, missionary to San Augustine and Nacogdoches, rector of Christ Church (Matagorda); notes on his life and career.
  - Allen, John K. (1810-1838) and Augustus C. (1806-1864), 253024 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Founders of Houston; notes on Baldwin, Rice, and Allen families
  - Allen, Samuel W. (1850s), 253023 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    of Harris County
  - Andrews, Stephen Pearl (1812-1886), 253022 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Notes on life and career of this Houston lawyer and translator, organizer of First Baptist Church (Houston), ardent abolitionist who attempted scheme to free enslaved persons with British money; portion of AFM article on S.P. Andrews; photocopy of brief in Eliza M. Westall & Wm. G. Hill vs. James F. Perry & Wife (Andrews the attorney for plaintiffs in this suit over the S.F. Austin Estate)
  - Army, 253021 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Notes and references to officers of the U.S. Volunteers from Texas in the war with Mexico (1846-1848); officers of the Regular Army who were killed, wounded or captured in Texas (1846-1872); West Point graduates who died in Texas (1845-1867); brief career sketches of West Point graduates whose activities touched Texas at one time or another (mid-19th century).
  - Audubon, John James (1785-1851), 253020 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Notes on references to Texas flora, fauna, and wildlife in Audubon's works and letters; notes on Audubon's trip to Texas (1837); references to works on or by Audubon; John James Jr.'s trip to Texas (1845)
  - Ault, William, 253019 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Deacon 1897 Honolulu
  - Austin, James E. Brown, 253018 (Box 24, Folder 10-12)
    Brother of Stephen F. Austin. Notes on records of contested administration of estate of James E. Brown Austin (1837); photocopies of documents: 1. deed, S.F. Austin executor of Santiago (James) E.B. Austin to Michael Scanlin via J.W. Collins (1829-1831) 2.) Deed in Spanish: Jas. B. Austin to William C. White (March 31, 1828)
    12 deeds to Santiago (James) E.B. (1824-1829) from: John F. Webber, Austin. McFarland, John Rabb, William Harvey, Peter Demoss, John Crownover, A.W.McClain, John Randon, Simon Miller, Elias R. Wightman, Frederick Rankin, William and John Cummings; abstracts of titles in inventories concerning lands sold to James E.B. Austin.
  - Austin, John (1801-1833), 253017 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Notes on John Austin, his life and career, his intended duel with William H. Wharton; photocopy of his instrument founding the city of Brazoria; photocopy of inventory of his estate; photocopy of petition of James F. Perry, executor of Stephen F. Austin (1837)
  - Austin, Stephen F., 253016 (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
    Research concerning titles to lands in Stephen F. Austin estate; litigation concerning the estate; abstracts from deed records, probate case records, inventories, affadavits, petitions; photocopies of executor's accounts; correspondence and articles referring to Austin estate, photocopy of transcription of Austin's will (1833) and a petition for probate (1837).
  - Austin, Stephen F., 253015 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
    Certified copies of land titles issued to S.F. Austin; references to Austin lands in "The Spanish Archives of the General Land Office of Texas," By Virginia Taylor (1955)
  - Austin, Stephen F., 253014 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of documents: 16 deeds to S.F. Austin from John Edward Dickerson, Phillip Singleton, Luke Moore, John D. Taylor, Mrs. L.A. White, Horatio Chriesman, Achilles McFarland, William Selkirk, William Parker, Alfred Kennon, Thomas Powell, Augustus Hotchkiss, Freeman Pettus, James W. Jones, and Robert Kuykendall; notes on deeds
  - Austin, Stephen F., 253013 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Will and proof: Photocopy of a transcript of the will of S.F. Austin, Deceased (dated April 19, 1833; entered into the probate March 27, 1843); references and notes on entries in the records of Texas counties relating to the will and codicil of Stephen F. Austin
  - Austin, Stephen F., Jr., 253012 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Brief notes on death of Stephen F. Austin Jr. (1828/29-1837), son of James E.B. Austin, nephew of Stephen F. Austin
  - Autry family (1794-1950), 253011 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    James L. Autry, member of colonial family of Texas, county judge, pioneer lawyer in new oil industry, an executive of the Texas Company (Texaco). Autry collection (at WRC) includes papers of James L. Autry (1830-1862), lieutenant colonel in C.S.A. and speaker of the Mississippi House; and Micajah Autry (?-1836) who died at the Alamo. Notes on lives and careers of members of the Autry family.
  - Autry House, 253010 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography by subject, 253009 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Muir's lists of sources by subjects
  - (Checklist of) Bibliographical Guides to the Sources and Literature of United States History, compiled by Barnes F. Lathrop, revised1960, and with revisions by AFM, 1966, 253008 (Box 26, Folder -)
  - Bailey, James Brit, 253007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Brookes Ono, d. 1913, 253006 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Physician at Kona, Roman Catholic priest
  - Baker, Daniel, 253005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Presbyterian evangelist, namesake of Daniel Baker College in Brownwood, Texas
  - Baker, Joe H., 253004 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Genealogy materials and notes on related families on central and southeast Texas: Menke, Bettis, von Rosenberg, Baker, Affleck, and Hass (late 18th through 20th centuries)
  - Balls (1837), 253003 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Brief notes on balls given in the Republic of Texas, taken from newspapers.
  - Bankrupts, 253002 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Notes on bankrupts in the Probate Records of Harris County, 1842-44, filed under the law passed Feb. 19, 1841.
  - Banks and Banking, 253001 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    Texas, 19th century. Notes on laws of the Texan Congress and legislature concerning regulation or prohibition of banking activities, references in newspapers, court cases involving companies performing acts of banking, early charters, commercial houses operating as banks, first banks under National Bank Act of 1863.
  - Barnes, William Henry, 253000 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Church deacon, Hawaii, 1880s
  - Batterson, Isaac, 1792-1838, 252999 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Texas mail carrier, 1836. Early resident of what is now Clinton, Harris County, Texas. Member of Austin's colony (1834); notes on Batterson and Harrell families.
  - Benchley, Henry Weatherby, 1822-1867, 252998 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Benson, Ellis, 252997 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    San Jacinto veteran. Coroner, Houston, Texas, 1860s
  - Blackburn, Thomas, 252996 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    Curate of Greenhithe, Kent, 1871, at Diocese of Honolulu 1878.
  - Blundun, Thomas, d. 1909, 252995 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    Priest and missionary in Honolulu and Victoria, Vancouver Island.
  - Bradley, Palmer, 252994 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    Houston attorney, 1950s-1960s correspondence with AFM.
  - Bridger, John, d. 1911, 252993 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    Deacon, Hawaii, 1870s-
  - Brownsville, TX, 252992 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Slave trade 1840s, causes of death in general population 1860s-1870s
  - Bryans & Perrys vs. Hill, 1855, 252991 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    Reproduction of case papers of W.J. Bryan et al vs. W.G. Hill, adminsitrator of Eliza M. Hill, deceased (1855) in Brazoria County District Court over lands inherited by Eliza M. Hill from estate of Stephen F. Austin
  - Burleson County, Texas, 252990 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    Reproduction of case papers of W.J. Bryan et al vs. W.G. Hill, administrator of Eliza M. Hill, deceased (1855) in Brazoria County District Court over lands inherited by Eliza M. Hill from estate of Stephen F. Austin
  - Burnet, David Gouverneur, 252989 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    U.S. Consul, Galveston, 1834. Includes AFM's introduction to "Letters on a Proposed War Criminal Trial, 1836". Notes regarding correspondence with Jefferson Davis.
  - Burr, Aaron, 252988 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Byrde, Louis, d. 1917, 252987 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    Graduate of Corpus Christi College, Cambridge. Reverend and missionary worker, Archdeacon (1915). Served in Victoria, Hong Kong and Yungchow, Hunan.
  - Cain, J. Isaiah, 252986 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Calder, William, d. 1923, 252985 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    Priest, Honolulu, ordained 1875. Succeeded Frederick Charles Lloyd. Vicar of All Saints, Auckland, New Zealand, 1883, archdeacon 1901.
  - Camels in Texas, 1836-1876, 252984 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    Notes on importation of camels in Texas for Army transportation; Jefferson Davis' plan to use camels during his term as Secretary of War; Robert E. Lee; programs for civilian use of camels for transportation; notes taken from newspapers, published letter collections, government imprints, secondary accounts, journal articles, congressional journals and documents, published memoirs, reference works, theses, acts of legislature, contemporary magazine articles, "The War of the Rebellion."
  - Cattle, 252983 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    Texas newspaper references 1850s-1860s on cattle drives, sales, industry, sheep, livestock and equipment.
  - Cemeteries, Texas, 252976
    Transcriptions of text on gravestones, including names, dates, epitaphs, and in some cases physical descriptions of the monuments. Typescript of AFM article "Nineteenth Century Texas Epitaphs".
    - Anderson - Hidalgo Counties, 252982 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Harris - Montgomery Counties, 252981 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Navarro - Whartox Counties, 252980 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - State Cemetery, Austin, 252979 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Notes on state laws establishing the state cemetery at Austin.
    - Houston, notecards arranged by deceased's name, 252978 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Episcopal Cemetery, Houston, 252977 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Cemeteries, Texas & Hawaii, 252975 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Notes on specific cemeteries, and AFM's writings on 19th century cemeteries in these locations.
  - Chambers, Thomas Jefferson, 252974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Diary typescript, 1837
  - Chapman, Robert Martin, 1810-1883, 252973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Anglican priest, missionary to Texas in 1838
  - Charlot, Nathaniel Peck (1850s-1860s), 252972 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    Anglican priest at Cold Springs (Polk County, Texas) and at Huntsville, former Presbyterian minister; notes on his career.
  - Charwane, Mary Hayes - estate, 1940-1944, 252971 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Chase, D.W. (?-1875), 252970 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    Anglican deacon, missionary to Grace Church (Independence, Texas); notes on his career.
  - Chilton, Thomas (1798-1854), 252969 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    Houston minister (1851), author of David Crockett's autobiography.
  - Church, 252944
    - Albertina (Sister) (1840-1930), 252968 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      St. Andrew's Priory, Hawaii. Notes on her career.
    - All Saint's Chapel, Austin, TX, 1940s-1950s, 252967 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Anglican clergy: copies of birth, death, and marriage certificates, vital statistics, 19th century, 252966 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Anglo-Catholicism, 252965 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      Newspaper references, excerpts from clergy diaries, 19th century, on the controversy of ritualism in the Anglican rite; Viscount Halifax (d. 1934); Rev. T. Pelham Dale (1880); references in "Punch" Rev. Arthur Tooth (1839-1930/31), Thomas Thellusson Carter, Tractarianism.
    - "BAA 435", 252964 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      Bibliography and references regarding the Tractarian or Oxford Movement of nineteenth century Britain.
    - Beatrice, Sister, d. 1921, 252963 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      St. Andrew's Priory, Honolulu, Hawaii. Notes on her career.
    - Bertha, Mother, d. 1890, 252962 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Notes on her career.
    - Bible in Texas, 1816-1871, 252961 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Notes on the activities of the American Bible Society throughout Texas; notes on various topics: Wharton family, Union Land Co., free Negroes, Logan family of Fort Bend County, bibliographical materials in Fondren Library, Federal census of Texas, Davis family of Fort Bend County, Coushatta tribe and Indians, Jose Antonio Mejia, George Lewis Hammeken, Henry Watkins Allen, McNabb family of Fort Bend and Brazoria Counties, photocopies of manuscripts concerning Galveston Bay & Texas Land Company.
    - Boerne, TX - church in, 252960 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Notes on religious life in Boerne (Kendall County) taken from state laws, imprints of the Episcopal church, reference works, monographs, deed records, tombstones; article "No Sabbath in West Texas: Missionary Appeals from Boerne, 1867-1868" edited with intro by AFM (published).
    - Christ Church, Houston, 252959 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Notes 1843-1948 taken from newspapers, church burial register, baptismal records, marriage registers, civil case papers of district court, deed records, unpublished memoirs, abstract of title, monographs, Episcopalian publications, journals of the Texas Congress, unpublished manuscripts, vestry records.
    - Church, correspondence on, 252958 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      AFM correspondence for research on the Anglican Church in Australia, Hawaii, and Texas.
    - Episcopal Church, 19th century, Texas, 252957 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Transcriptions of manuscripts pertaining to the organization of the first convention of the Episcopal Church in Texas (1843); transcription of the register of St. Peter's Church, Brenham, Texas (1869-1885)
    - Episcopal Church record, 19th century, Texas, 252956 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Episcopal Church marriages, 19th century, Texas, 252955 (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
    - Episcopal Church reformed, 19th century, Texas, 252954 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Brief notes (1874-1894) on activities of and references to Reformed Episcopal Church in Harris, Travis, and Fort Bend Counties, and states of Colorado and Missouri.
    - FTA 452, 252953 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Loose-leaf volume of notes on references of Tractarianism (Oxford Movement), Newmanism, Puseyism, Anglo-Catholicism.
    - Ingreja Evangelica Lusitana (Portugese Evangelical Church), 19th century, 252952 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Brief notes on movements in Portugal and Spain (1870s) to establish congregations with Anglican rites. Materials are in Portugese, Spanish and English.
    - Lay reading, 252951 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Mary Clara, Sister, d. 1884, 252950 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      St. Andrew's Priory, Hawaii. Notes on her career and death.
    - Phoebe, Eldress, d. 1890, 252949 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Roman Catholics in Houston and Fort Bend County, 1840-1872, 252948 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Notes on marriages and other general topics.
    - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, Houston, TX, 1940s-1950s, 252947 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Newsclippings, general outgoing correspondence
    - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, Y.P.S.L. committee minutes, Houston, TX, 1930s, 252946 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Original handwritten meeting minutes.
    - YT 401, 252945 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Notes on references to Anglo-Catholocism in the works of Agatha Christie; references to comments concerning Anglo-Catholocism in various literary works.
  - Clark, Abel, d. 1885, 252943 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    Deacon, Hawaii
  - Clark, Horace, 1819-1909, 252942 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    Early Texas Baptist preacher, Washington County. Educator, principal/president of Baylor Female College at Independence, Texas (1851-1871), converted to Episcopal Church, rector of the Episcopal Church at Corpus Christi (1880-1897); notes on his life and career, references to Clark.
  - Cline, M.H., 252941 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    Member of Williams Chapter of Order of DeMolay, San Benito - Harlingen, TX. One outgoing letter, n.d.
  - Clopper, Andrew May, 1791-1853, 252940 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Son of Nicholas Clopper. Texas revolutionary solider of Harris County. Notes relating to Battle of San Jacinto, real estate.
  - Clopper, Nicholas, Jr., 252939 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    Notes and correspondence regarding Texas land grants, 1820s and 1830s
  - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland, 1818-1896, 252938 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    Episcopalian, elected Bishop of Texas, 1856, originally from Baltimore. Declined positions as Bishop of Texas and Rector of Christ Church, Houston. Notes and transcriptions of correspondence.
  - Cloud, Adam, 1759-1834, 252937 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    Episcopalian priest in Mississippi, Georgia, and Texas. Member of Austin's colony, 1830/31.
  - Cloud, John Wurts, 252936 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    Anglican priest, resident of Washington-on-the-Brazos, revolutionary soldier, founder of a school at Brazoria. Typescript of autobiography, notes regarding real estate, career, Johnston family of Brazoria, Asa Brigham; AFM typescript article on J.W. Cloud.
  - Congress, Texan, 1836-1838, 252935 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    List of members of the Senate and House of the First and Second Congresses (1836-1838), surveys of journals and proceedings of the House and Senate of the First Congress, 1st and 2nd Sessions, and of journal of the House for Called Session (Sept. 1837) and Regular Session (Second Congress, First Session).
  - Connelly, Pierce, 1804-1883, 252934 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Anglican priest of the old South, convert to CatholCatholicismcism; Anglicanism in Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama.
  - Consulate, United States, 1827-1837, 252933 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Transcripts of correspondence from Mexico (including parts of what is now Texas) to local offices of the US Consulate. Also includes lists of consuls' names and locations of offices.
  - Crockett, David, 252932 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Cross, Joseph, 252931 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Episcopalian priest, elected 1867; brief notes on career in Houston.
  - Cullen, Ezekiel Wimberley, 252930 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Texas real estate notes, 1870s
  - Curtis, Judson, 252929 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    Episcopalian priest, rector of Christ Church, Houston 1864-1866.
  - DaGama, Elizabeth Bell (Bates) Volck Hearn, 187?-1937, 252928 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    Widow of the Brazilian ambassador to U.S. (1911-1918), possibly related to the Bates family of Brazoria County, divorce case handled by Albert T. Patrick (1890)
  - Dahlgren's Furniture Studio, Houston, TX, 1940s, 252927 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Dalzell, William Tucker Dickinson, 1826/27-19??, 252926 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Anglican priest, born in St. Vincent, West Indies, educated in medicine and theology at London, rector of Christ Church, Houston 1857-1861.
  - Davis Guards, 1861-1865, 252925 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    Notes on military record of every member of the Davis Guards, arranged in alphabetical order; Dick Dowling and Sabine Pass.
  - Davis, Sam. L. [HY], 252924 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Delhi-Taylor Oil Corporation, 252923 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Brochures, annual reports, 1959-1961
  - Denison, Samuel Dexter, 252922 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Episcopalian priest, rector of Christ Church, Matagorda, 1850
  - Desha, John Rollins Langherne, 1819-1871, 252921 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    Druggist, of Hawaii, originally from Kentucky
  - Dewees, William B., 252920 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    Early settler of Texas
  - Dickinson, Susanna (1815-1883) and her "Babe of the Alamo" Angelina Elizabeth Dickinson (1835-1869), 252919 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    Notes on the fall of the Alamo, life of Angelina E. Dickinson; certified copies of legal briefs of Peter Bellows vs. Susannah Bellows (1857) and Susan Williams v. John Williams (1838).
  - Dictionary of Texan English on Historical Principles, 252918 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    Terms used in the Texas during the period of the Republic, taken from Joseph E. Field "Three Years in Texas" (1836): typed definitions of terms such as "elm bottoms", "pecan", "yellowskin".
  - Divorces, Texas, 19th century, 252917 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    Handwritten lists of divorces in various Texas counties, notes on divorces issued by the Congress of the Republic or by the district courts of Orange, Jefferson, Travis, Montgomery, and Harris Counties, 1839-1861.
  - Dobie family, 1838-1910, 252916 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    Notes on land deeds in Harris County.
  - Dobie, James Frank (J. Frank), 252915 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Notes and original correspondence, 1959-1960
  - Dowling, Richard William, 1838-1867, 252914 (Box 33, Folder 12-14)
    U.S. Civil War veteran of Texas, fought in Battle of Sabine Pass. Notes on Davis Guards, and Dowling's relatives including Odlum and Shearn families.
  - Dowling, Richard William, 1838-1867, 252913 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Downing, Elijah H., 252912 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Episcopalian priest at Brenham and Chapell Hill (1855-1857), missionary and rector of Christ Church at San Augustine and Christ Church at Nacogdoches (1851-1854). Notes on his career.
  - Dueling, 19th century, 252911 (Box 34, Folder 3)